<dashboard>
 <label>Introduction</label>
  
  <row>
   <html>
<h1>Welcome to the Splunk App for Microsoft SharePoint</h1>

<p>This app is designed to provide comprehensive data collection and field extraction from Microsoft SharePoint 2010 or SharePoint
2013 and a set of starting dashboards covering health, audit and usage.  The data collection includes the following:</p>
<ul>
 <li>SharePoint Object Inventory</li>
 <li>Service and Performance Information</li>
 <li>Network Latency Information</li>
 <li>IIS Logs</li>
 <li>ULS Logs</li>
 <li>SharePoint Audit Logs</li>
</ul>

<p>This app will not work until all installation is completed.  The installation process will take some time and some adjustment 
to the permissions structures that govern the SharePoint farm.</p>

<h2>System Requirements</h2>

<p>The "central Splunk instance" (consisting of search heads and indexers) can be any operating system.  You must be running
Splunk v6.0 or later on all Splunk servers within the central Splunk instance.  Splunk v5.0 is no longer supported.</p>

<p>Splunk App for Microsoft SharePoint supports:</p>

<ul>
<li>Microsoft SharePoint 2010 running on Windows Server 2008R2</li>
<li>Microsoft SharePoint 2013 running on Windows Server 2008R2</li>
<li>SQL Server 2008R2 running on Windows Server 2008R2</li>
<li>SQL Server 2012 running on Windows Server 2012</li>
</ul>

<p>To start, click on <a href="docs_1install">Installation</a>.</p>

<h2>New In This Version<h2>

<p>In this version, we have done the following:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Converted all services to use Splunk 6.0 techniques.</li>
	<li>Reduced the permissions required to run the Audit and Inventory service - please refer to the installation instructions.</li>
	<li>Removed the need for the TA-Windows-* from the Universal Forwarder.  You should remove this add-on from your SharePoint servers.</li>
	<li>Removed the dependence on specific indices.  Ensure all users who access the Splunk App for SharePoint search the relevant indices by default.  A role has been added to make this easier.</li>
</ul>

   </html>
  </row>
 </dashboard>