<dashboard>
 <label>Installation</label>
 <row>
   <html>
<h2>Step 1: Install the Splunk App for SQL Server on all Content Servers</h2>

<p>The backend storage for SharePoint is SQL Server.  Install the Splunk App for SQL Server, which is available on Splunkbase,
prior to commencing work on SharePoint.  Ensure that audit data for access and database operations are flowing into Splunk
and that all SQL Server health and performance data is being recorded and showing in the dashboards for that app prior to
commencing the Splunk App for SharePoint installation.  Installation Documentation for the Splunk App for SQL Server is
available with that app.</p>

<p>At least Splunk App for SQL Server v0.1.6 is required.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Prepare the Splunk Indexers</h2>

<p>Create the following indices in the Splunk Indexers:</p>
<ul>
<li>perfmon</li>
<li>mssharepoint</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition, you must deploy the TA-Sharepoint20XX app to the Indexers.  This app is contained within the appserver/addons
area of the Splunk App for SharePoint.  There is a different app for SharePoint 2010 and SharePoint 2013.  Only one version
of the app is needed (and the data is common to both versions of SharePoint, so either one will work).  You will need to restart 
the splunkd process to register this app on each indexer.  You can disable the inputs within this app as they are not necessary. </p>

<p>The TA-Sharepoint20XX handles augmented line breaking and data fixing of the ULS logs so that each transaction is available as
a single event instead of multiple events.  This is required for exception reporting within the dashboards.</p>

<h2>Step 3: Designate an Inventory and Audit Reader</h2>

<p>One of your SharePoint servers must be designated as an inventory and audit reader.  This server will be used to gather the
inventory information and to read the audit log within SharePoint.  The Universal Forwarder that is installed on this SharePoint 
server will need special handling.</p>

<p>If you have multiple farms, then you must designate an Inventory and Audit Reader in each farm.</p>

<h2>Step 4: Install Splunk on the other SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>Each SharePoint server that is not the Inventory and Audit Reader host can get a standard "Local System" type install of
the latest Splunk Universal Forwarder (version v5.0.3 or later).  It should be linked to a Splunk Deployment Server so that you
can easily push updated apps to the Universal Forwarder.  It should be sending data to the central Splunk instance.</p>

<h2>Step 5: Install Splunk on the Inventory and Audit Reader</h2>

<p>The Splunk Universal Forwarder that is running on the Inventory and Audit Reader must be running as a domain account.
The domain accounts must have the following characteristics:</p>

<ul>
<li>Local Administrator</li>
<li>SharePoint Farm Administrator</li>
<li>PowerShell Administrator</li>
<li>sysadmin on each Content Database Server</li>
<li>Secondary Owner on every site collection</li>
</ul>

<p>These are wide-ranging permissions, which is why they are limited to just one machine.  The "inventory" task requires that
the user executing the script be a SharePoint PowerShell administrator and the "sharepoint audit log" reader requires access
to every single database on the content database server as the audit log is spread across multiple databases.</p>

<p>If you have multiple farms, then the user involved may be different for each farm.</p>

<h2>Step 6: Deploy Add-ons to the SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>The following add-ons need to be deployed to each server:</p>

<ul>
<li>Splunk_TA_windows (Splunk Technology Add-on for Microsoft Windows, available from Splunkbase) v4.6 or later</li>
<li>TA-Sharepoint20XX (provided with the app in appserver/addons - XX is 10 or 13, depending on your SharePoint version)</li>
<li>TA-Windows2008R2-IIS (provided with the app in appserver/addons)</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition, the Inventory and Audit Reader must have the TA-Sharepoint20XX-Audit add-on, which is provided with the
app in appserver/addons.</p>

<h2>Step 7: Add cs-host to the SharePoint site logging</h2>

<p>Normally, the full URL that the user types in is not available in the logs.  You need to adjust the logging specification
for each web site in IIS as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open up the IIS Manager</li>
<li>Select the SharePoint Site</li>
<li>Select Logging</li>
<li>Click on Select Fields</li>
<li>Check the box next to cs-host</li>
<li>Click on OK</li>
<li>Under Actions, click on Apply</li>
<li>Repeat steps 2-7 for each additional SharePoint site and host</li>
</ol>

<p>This needs to be completed on each SharePoint host that answers IIS queries (which is generally all of them).</p>

<h2>Step 8: Wait 24 hours</h2>

<p>We need some data from the inventory and this is gathered on a regular basis at night.  Since it is impactful to the Inventory
and Audit Reader, we have limited its scope to once a day.</p>

<h2>Step 9: Regenerate Lookup Files</h2>

<p>Each lookup has an associated entry under Searches &amp; Reports -> Lookup Generators.  Run each search in turn and ensure 
they produce data.  The app as a whole will not work without the functioning lookups.</p>

<h2>Step 10: Check Errors</h2>

<p>Log into Splunk and open the Splunk App for SharePoint.  Select Health -> Farm Errors.  All errors in this report are significant.</p>

<p>If you see errors like the following:</p>

<pre>Inventory cannot access site http://sharepoint.bd.splunk.com/sites/windows - BD\SP_service is not listed as Owner or SecondaryContact</pre>

<p>This is indicative that a site collection has not been configured with the proper permissions.  See Step 5 above, add the listed user
as a Secondary Owner on that site collection.</p>

   </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>