<dashboard>
 <label>Installation</label>
 <row>
   <html>
<h2>Step 1: Install the Splunk App for SQL Server on all Content Servers</h2>

<p>The backend storage for SharePoint is SQL Server. Install the Splunk App for 
SQL Server, which is available on Splunkbase, prior to commencing work on SharePoint. 
Ensure that audit data fordatabase operations and perfmon data are flowing into 
Splunk and that all SQL Server health and performance data is being recorded and 
showing in the dashboards for that app prior to commencing the Splunk App for 
SharePoint installation. You do not need to provide the query audit for the 
database. Installation Documentation for the Splunk App for SQL Server is 
available with that app. At least Splunk App for SQL Server v0.1.8 is required.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Prepare the Splunk Indexers</h2>

<p>Create the following indices in the Splunk Indexers:</p>
<ul>
<li>perfmon</li>
<li>iis</li>
<li>mssharepoint</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition, you must deploy the TA-Sharepoint20XX app to the Indexers.  This 
app is contained within the appserver/addons area of the Splunk App for SharePoint.  
There is a different app for SharePoint 2010 and SharePoint 2013.  Only one version 
of the app is needed (and the data is common to both versions of SharePoint, so 
either one will work).  You will need to restart the splunkd process to register 
this app on each indexer.  You can disable the inputs within this app as they are 
not necessary. </p> 

<p>The TA-Sharepoint20XX handles augmented line breaking and data fixing of the 
ULS logs so that each transaction is available as a single event instead of 
multiple events.  This is required for exception reporting within the dashboards.</p>

<h2>Step 3: Designate an Inventory and Audit Reader</h2>

<p>One of your SharePoint servers must be designated as an inventory and audit 
reader.  This server will be used to gather the inventory information and to read 
the audit log within SharePoint.  The Universal Forwarder that is installed on this 
SharePoint server will need special handling.</p>

<p>If you have multiple farms, then you must designate an Inventory and Audit Reader 
in each farm.</p>

<h2>Step 4: Install Splunk on the other SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>Each SharePoint server that is not the Inventory and Audit Reader host can get 
a standard "Local System" type install of the latest Splunk Universal Forwarder 
(version v6.0 or later).  It should be linked to a Splunk Deployment Server so 
that you can easily push updated apps to the Universal Forwarder.  It should be 
sending data to the central Splunk instance.</p>

<h2>Step 5: Install Splunk on the Inventory and Audit Reader</h2>

<p>The Splunk Universal Forwarder that is running on the Inventory and Audit 
Reader must be running as a domain account.  The domain accounts must have the 
following characteristics:</p>

<ul>
<li>Local Administrator</li>
<li>Add-SPShellAdmin (PowerShell Farm Administrator)</li>
</ul>

<p>To add the database permissions properly, ensure you run the following command 
using machine administrator from a farm administrator account that has shell admin 
privileges to SharePoint_Config:</p>

<pre>Get-SPDatabase | Add-SPShellAdmin -UserName 'DOMAIN\user'</pre>

<p>Where DOMAIN\user is the username of the user running the Splunk Universal 
Forwarder.</p>

<p>If you have multiple farms, then the user involved is probably different for 
each farm.  Each farm will need their own Inventory and Audit Reader.</p>

<h2>Step 6: Deploy Add-ons to the SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>The following add-ons need to be deployed to each server:</p>

<ul>
<li>Splunk_TA_windows v4.6.4 or later</li>
<li>TA-Sharepoint20XX (provided with the app in appserver/addons)</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition, the Inventory and Audit Reader must have the TA-Sharepoint20XX-Audit 
add-on, which is provided with the app in appserver/addons.</p>

<h2>Step 7: Add cs-host to the SharePoint site logging</h2>

<p>Normally, the full URL that the user types in is not available in the logs.  
You need to adjust the logging specification for each web site in IIS as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open up the IIS Manager</li>
<li>Select the SharePoint Site</li>
<li>Select Logging</li>
<li>Click on Select Fields</li>
<li>Check the box next to cs-host</li>
<li>Click on OK</li>
<li>Under Actions, click on Apply</li>
<li>Repeat steps 2-7 for each additional SharePoint site and host</li>
</ol>

<p>This needs to be completed on each SharePoint host that answers IIS queries 
(which is generally all of them).</p>

<h2>Step 8: Add Users to the SharePoint role</h2>

<p>Part of the app install will also enable a sharepoint role.  Add users that will 
view the SharePoint data to the sharepoint role.  Without this step, they may not 
be able to see the relevant data.  As an alternative to this process, you can also 
edit the eventtypes supplied with the app to indicate which index the data resides 
in.</p>

<h2>Step 8: Wait 1 hour</h2>

<p>We need some data from the inventory and this is gathered on a regular basis.  
In general, this data is collected within the first hour of operation.</p>

<h2>Step 9: Regenerate Lookup Files</h2>

<p>There is a dashboard under Searches and Reports -> Lookup Generators called 
the Lookup Table Builder. Use it to generate all the lookup tables.</p>

<h2>Step 10: Check Errors</h2>

<p>Log into Splunk and open the Splunk App for SharePoint.  Select 
Health -> Farm Errors.  All errors in this report are significant.</p>

<h2>Errors</h2>

<p>If the modular inputs show errors, they will show up in the splunkd.log file.  The most common will be something to the 
effect "SPFarm.Local == null", which would indicate a permissions problem.  Specifically, the user that is being used to run 
the Splunk Universal Forwarder on the Audit and Inventory reader has not been added to the SPShellAdmin list with 
Add-SPShellAdmin.</p>

<p>If you get Farm Errors showing an SqlException 80131904, then it is likely that you have not provided access to all the
databases.  Log on to the Central Administration host as a farm administrator with shell admin rights on SharePoint_Config;
bring up a PowerShell host using "Run as Administrator", and type the following:</p>

<pre>Add-PsSnapIn Microsoft.SharePoint.PowerShell
Get-SPDatabase | Add-SPShellAdmin -UserName 'DOMAIN\user'</pre>

<p>Replace the DOMAIN\user with the username of the user running the Splunk Universal Forwarder.</p>

   </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>
