<dashboard>
 <label>Installation</label>
 <row>
   <html>
<h2>Step 1: Install the Splunk App for SQL Server on all Content SQL Servers</h2>

<p>The backend storage for SharePoint is SQL Server. Install the Splunk App for 
SQL Server, which is available on Splunkbase, prior to commencing work on SharePoint. 
Ensure that audit data for database operations and perfmon data are flowing into 
Splunk and that all SQL Server health and performance data is being recorded and 
showing in the dashboards for that app prior to commencing the Splunk App for 
SharePoint installation. You do not need to provide the query audit for the 
database. Installation Documentation for the Splunk App for SQL Server is 
available with that app. At least Splunk App for SQL Server v0.1.8 is required.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Prepare the Splunk Indexers</h2>

<p>Install the appropriate TA-Sharepoint20XX on the indexers and restart them. These
add-ons are available on <a href="http://apps.splunk.com">apps.splunk.com</a> and must
be configured separately.</p>

<p>The TA-Sharepoint20XX add-on handles augmented line breaking and data fixing of the 
ULS logs so that each transaction is available as a single event instead of 
multiple events.  This is required for exception reporting within the dashboards.
In addition, the TA-Sharepoint20XX add-on installs the required indices.</p>

<h2>Step 3: Prepare your Sharepoint servers</h2>

<p>The documentation provided with the TA-Sharepoint20XX add-on specifies the required
configuration changes on your Sharepoint servers.</p>

<h2>Step 4: Install the Splunk Universal Forwarder on the SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>Refer to the documentation within the TA-Sharepoint20XX regarding the permissions
required, taking special note of the Audit and Inventory Reader system.</p>

<h2>Step 6: Deploy Add-ons to the SharePoint servers</h2>

<p>The following add-ons need to be deployed to each server:</p>

<ul>
<li>Splunk_TA_windows v4.6.6 or later</li>
<li>SA-ModularInput-PowerShell</li>
<li>TA-Sharepoint20XX v0.2.0 or later</li>
</ul>

<p>Note that Technology Addons are distributed with data inputs disabled.  Ensure
you enable the data inputs appropriate to the function.  Only enable the sp1Xaudit
and sp1Xinventory on your Inventory and Audit Reader.  Enable all other inputs
on all machines.</p>

<h2>Step 7: Add cs-host to the SharePoint site logging</h2>

<p>Normally, the full URL that the user types in is not available in the logs.  
You need to adjust the logging specification for each web site in IIS as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open up the IIS Manager</li>
<li>Select the SharePoint Site</li>
<li>Select Logging</li>
<li>Click on Select Fields</li>
<li>Check the box next to cs-host</li>
<li>Click on OK</li>
<li>Under Actions, click on Apply</li>
<li>Repeat steps 2-7 for each additional SharePoint site and host</li>
</ol>

<p>This needs to be completed on each SharePoint host that answers IIS queries 
(which is generally all of them).</p>

<h2>Step 8: Add Users to the SharePoint role</h2>

<p>Part of the app install will also enable a sharepoint role.  Add users that will 
view the SharePoint data to the sharepoint role.  Without this step, they may not 
be able to see the relevant data.  As an alternative to this process, you can also 
edit the eventtypes supplied with the app to indicate which index the data resides 
in.</p>

<h2>Step 8: Wait 1 hour</h2>

<p>We need some data from the inventory and this is gathered on a regular basis.  
In general, this data is collected within the first hour of operation.</p>

<h2>Step 9: Regenerate Lookup Files</h2>

<p>There is a dashboard under Searches and Reports -> Lookup Generators called 
the Lookup Table Builder. Use it to generate all the lookup tables.</p>

<h2>Step 10: Check Errors</h2>

<p>Log into Splunk and open the Splunk App for SharePoint.  Select 
Health -> Farm Errors.  All errors in this report are significant.</p>

<h2>Errors</h2>

<p>If the modular inputs show errors, they will show up in the splunkd.log file.  The most common will be something to the 
effect "SPFarm.Local == null", which would indicate a permissions problem.  Specifically, the user that is being used to run 
the Splunk Universal Forwarder on the Audit and Inventory reader has not been added to the SPShellAdmin list with 
Add-SPShellAdmin.</p>

<p>If you get Farm Errors showing an SqlException 80131904, then it is likely that you have not provided access to all the
databases.  Log on to the Central Administration host as a farm administrator with shell admin rights on SharePoint_Config;
bring up a PowerShell host using "Run as Administrator", and type the following:</p>

<pre>Add-PsSnapIn Microsoft.SharePoint.PowerShell
Get-SPDatabase | Add-SPShellAdmin -UserName 'DOMAIN\user'</pre>

<p>Replace the DOMAIN\user with the username of the user running the Splunk Universal Forwarder on the Inventory and Audit
Reader.</p>

   </html>
  </row>
</dashboard>
